<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>The loyall speech of Sir Richard Scott, recorder of the ancient town of Barwick upon Tweed spoken to His Royall Highness the Duke of York upon his entrance into Barwick.</title>
            <author>Scott, Richard, Sir.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1679</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 4 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 2 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A61694</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S5757</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R18741</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">11939758</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 11939758</idno>
            <idno type="VID">51255</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A61694)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 51255)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 515:37)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>The loyall speech of Sir Richard Scott, recorder of the ancient town of Barwick upon Tweed spoken to His Royall Highness the Duke of York upon his entrance into Barwick.</title>
                  <author>Scott, Richard, Sir.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet (2 p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[S.l. :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1679?]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Broadside.</note>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Huntington Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>James --  II, --  King of England, 1633-1701.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  London --  17th cnetury</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-05</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-05</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-06</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="speech">
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:51255:1"/>
            <head>THE LOYALL SPEECH OF Sir Richard Stott RECORDER of the Ancient TOWN of <hi>BARWICK</hi> upon <hi>TWEED.</hi>
            </head>
            <head type="sub">SPOKEN To His Royall Highneſs the Duke of <hi>YORK,</hi> upon his Entrance into <hi>Barwick.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <salute>May it pleaſe your Royal Highneſs,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>WE humbly and heartily congratulate your coming to this poor but Ancient Town, a place more conſiderable for its ſcituati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on then its fortune, yet happier now then in former times when it was made a Butt for the two Kingdoms to ſhoot at: Without our Walls (Great Sir) you may ſee thoſe Hills, where that Royall blood which runs (happily united) in your Princely veins, whilſt it was divided between your <hi>Engliſh</hi> and <hi>Scottiſh</hi> Anceſtors, did contend for Empire and for glory; and it is our happineſs that this place which was once the utmoſt limits of two great Kingdoms, is now the middle of our Soveraigns Dominions: We of this Corporation were the moſt ingratefull of Subjects, and the unworthieſt of men, if we did not pay all Duty and Obeyſanee to your Princely Perſon. Your Royall Grand-father (whoſe Sacred Name you bear) was our Founder; He gave us not only our Priviledges (which are great) but our ſubſiſtence which ſupports us: And he tells us plainly in his moſt munificent Charter, that he did it to oblige us to pay the greater Duty and Loyal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ty to him, and his Poſterity for ever: Your Royall Father (the Mir<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rour
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:51255:2"/>of Kings) was our Benefactor, and our Gracious Soveraign hath largely extended his Bounty to us, and we know that we cannot bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter expreſs our Duty and Loyalty to him, then in giving Teſtimony of it to you (Great Sir) his only Brother. We have yet powerfull motives from your ſelf: Your Noble and Heroick Actions have been the wonder of <hi>Europe,</hi> nor can any Loyall heart forget how boldly and prodigally you ventured your Life for the Honour and Proſperity of his Majeſty and theſe Kingdoms, when in the Year (63.) by the bleſſing of God upon your incomparable Valour and Conduct, you overthrew and van<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>quiſhed the Greateſt Fleet that ever the Sea bore: Then it was that you made <hi>Neptunes</hi> Trident bow and pay homage to the Engliſh Sceptre. Let the Ancient <hi>Romans</hi> tell us of their great Sea-Fight at <hi>Actium,</hi> be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tween <hi>Auguſtus</hi> and <hi>Mark Anthony.</hi> Let our own Hiſtories relate the fa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mous Victory of your Glorious Progenitor King <hi>Edward</hi> the 3. at <hi>Scluſe.</hi> Let the Modern Hiſtories of <hi>Europe</hi> declare that Celebrated Victory of <hi>Don John of Auſtria</hi> at the Battle of <hi>Lepanto,</hi> thoſe muſt all ſtrike ſail, and veil to your Glorious Triumph. If we ſearch the Annals of Former Ages, we can finde no thing like it; and it is more then probable that the Times to come may not produce a Parallel. What ſhall we then render to you (Great Prince) for ſuch inimitable Actions and Merits? All we can ſay is, that next after our Prayers for the long Life and Happy Reign of our moſt Gratious Sovereign, we ardently wiſh all en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>creaſe of Honour, Renown, and Happineſs to the Glorious JAMES his moſt Princely Brother.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
